Right it's almost too so I think we shouldget...
could often everyone on...would thank you guys for being here.
Because you see it's a friday afternoon post lunch.
Last session of the conference going to be talking about troubleshooting
...work in my favor so I really appreciate I've been here thank you very much
bye so with that say no we're going to talk about today well,
first of all my name is...sheI'm a program manager larger
app service theme I focus on building features from a bats the...spend the
...my career with microsoft the working as a support...so I've seen the
...customers go through when things don't work out very well and the one of the things that
I decided when I took this job to try and do things where?
I can help improve the situations for the scenarios where you have deploy the
sites...productions running full-blown and something's
bads happening right and now you really want to find out what's going on what can I do
troubleshooting and things along those lines because the tons and tons of solutions out there that basically go
and say no I'm going to give you alerting...this...for-you I'll let, you know, when something goes wrong
...you get a phone call you get a pager what's next right that's one stop people,
people start usually freaking out the pages loading slow of what to do next?
So, what we've done here and...with the...web app service?
Is an attend the to try and automate the diagnostics to a
point?
Where we can start?
Trying to give you a snapshot of what is happening in
...production site at any given time along the side with the prescriptive
guidance on what we think is going draw because most of the time for the developer you don't have
to...what...and how to fix it you just telling what has been screwed up
and he or she knows what to fix it right so that said we're?
Going-to go ahead...the start this session.
...this you guys know the usual drill ...and submit the valve there because it helps improve.
the agenda basically for this and the key take away I want you guys to go away from there has to understand
the tools and the best practices available to trouble shoot either web apps roger websites
or apps of is focusing on the performance and availability
...and the reason it's very important because the larger ad services
...fully manage fast solution where we don't allow you to artie p don't
...to install bunch of tools...and things along those lines so that makes troubleshooting a little bit of a
challengeand, basically what you should be
do when all the tools and everything else doesn't work what the next options are right?
Okay, so, we'll just...a fortify tops the at
...what could possibly go wrong...see all the situations are different kinds of issues we try and
...and...issues before we
start diving into how to use and tools because it's important to understand what kind of
issue your seen before you start using different tools...and you don't really don't use
this sledgehammer to try and put enable the to fans and things along those lines
...will to the tools that are available
...and lots of demos in a demo I'm going to start with the something very simple
...to how you start peeling the orleans-and fill in the final demos we'll start
look into some really, really advanced of...see how we can...helping so we should
live performance the issues with websites it's not going to be like I'm going to
open a visual studio and attaching debug and put a break point my prediction site...we want to
...show you what do you do in a situation when all those
known tools available to you don't work...take a lot of questions hopefully we'll have enough time for them.
So, what could possibly go wrong right?
It's...always a question on everyone's mind when you're
...under a very tight a deadline of...product if...a
...things along those lines I experience that every single time and when I was making this presentation last week,
you know, what my wife came and told
me a little my story about the my two-year-old and what happened and I thought it
was fantastic to show...you guys because it helps you
...helps us understand different kinds of issues whatnot here's what happened last week my
two-year-oldthat is the preschool had a session to take a picture was classmate
right so my wife is all excited like any whether she wants the picture-perfect my kid to
look very fantastic righty...up and she's she has a picture in our mind
...that's what this picture look like right so this...preparing for the one in the head is my little
...she's...this how it's going to be I'm going to prepare this thing in
a nice way and it's usually very nice kid like I'll think of them is a very...app
...is the good...my wife is trying to go through this process of getting this picture that
...suffused running late although...the kids started crying
and cheese freaking out she's like my god the pictures not going to look like this these crying right this is typical thing on...ship
...product I'm running out of time search cheated sites, you know,
what in the car?
I'm going to give mechanic it always works
...one can easily the heavy but he's using situation
...is advantages...one more she goes like
...give another candy...can possibly go wrong it's just a candy right so she gives
...candy third one right the kids all happy results talked up
...ready for the picture right it's all good.
You should the product.
And, this is what the picture turns out to be you see the...one here sitting next is best friend.
In the next and both of...on the floor right so this is how we turn out to be
...in that situation I...is very
the similar to how we do development and how we do a job development start
pushing things into production and things along those lines right at the industry astra what
...would you...the root class she was obviously the sugar right given too much of its
such a nice-guy of able web app I give...too much sugar that's what causes
...if I were to ask the same question to the victim's mother she's going to know
is that boy manny's is a very not evoke the...that to my
...if I were to ask my boss near what's the root causes...is a teacher they should never
make them sit together for the picture right so it's all different perspective and how you how
...troubleshooting things...put things into perspective right so it's very
important the to understand the type of the issue before we start jumping of
...into the...so every time you call into micros
...any live service support or any company
...at highly at high-level there are three different kinds of issues that we go through right so here,
you know, you perform...got a problem right?
First one is the most easy one it's a generic advocacy right or you want
to do something like subscription migration I want to move my acid from the subscript another one there's no
low-impact everything's happy it pick up the phone is...man how are you how's the weather
...to do this everything answer very happy most the time right.
The second one is you notice something crazy happening with website you
go like hey man this is weird in a...to do about this so you pick up a
phone...support and you report...with incident right
and this category has two kinds of issues the first one.
Is usually...issue but it's very difficult to isolate is an application issue
or a platform but right so you basically go through a whole cycle of working with the...trying to get the data try and
...at the end of the where's my day...to fix this right and...cycles
...brand...back...specific...
The other category here you repeat the whole cycle you call you go through process
...the support that tells you what we found out there's a bug in the platform
is impacting you maybe tens of other customers the entire services not dom
and then customer usually goes like a...suffix...going to ship it and things on those lines.
This is the second caddy that you see...
the major is the majority of the issues that support or any service usually goes through.
The third in the big one is my god there's a platform
...and usually the my god is coming from the service...itself is not the...usually
the customer because we have tons and tons of allergic and monitoring place where we
...sites there's a canary siphoning every single gm will try and see what the response time
is and the...and things along those lines we get the alert and we start freaking out when we get
dealer from any given stampa region and have...engineers up and
running usually doesn't come from customer but there are situations where this might be
...from customer because our monitoring catching nobody's, nobody's perfect and that's a learning process
we can we try and incorporate that into a learning process this...category there
isn't much you as a customer can do to actually resolve the issue in
most cases you're basically at the mercy of service owner to try and fix
issued all you need at that point...just tell me what's going on how long as going-to-take to fix
the issue and there's that?
Let's core what causes usually the platform issues
...specific dodger apps services because were built very uniquely write-in like
...likes to say right he when he talks about these two different compute
...in all I as is like a building your own house.
Has like a renting the house?
And, app service of the sites it's more like
a ranking luxury hotel right I mean basically everything...for use...using
it you'll get and things along those lines so when we build this large results always
been and basically using all the core services like...equalizer
...depend on network depend on cloud services where actually the largest
cloud service out there on microsoft roger platform right so you can see any of those component can
...or have an issue and devil impact...service we do have
...bunch of?
In all abstraction level on our...system to basically stay aware and try
and avoid this issues but, you know, things can go wrong...globally it can be any
stampa another that could be random bucks right so these are...things that could cause the platform issues
and there isn't much you can do unless.
Except for just one of the
...dashboard and try and see what the statuses in I'll be honest with you guys...right now
this dashboard updated is performed by humans right so you saw that
the large charles platform issue where we get dealer somebody says my god freaking out he gets
...start looking...and the next thing does
he calls the dashboard dicey update this basically see I'm having
xyz for right and...working towards automating this whole experience but that's what it
is sometimes when you see...site you come to dashboard you don't see anything and you go like why isn't there and
then half an hour fifteen minutes or whatever time it takes you probably have seen all there's no there is
this thing but it's usually up to date and is the only source?
Of information at this point to understand what's going on when the platform issue...
So, to this session we're going to focus on the second the middle category where,
you know, the self-help is possible this is where you can do something yourself
and trying to figure out what the could be the...and things along those lines.
So, what you can do today with address services you cannot
...the vm for?
Obvious design reasons the your application cannot...
The...have access to vm or a site uw or you can't...in the
...indeed pretty much makes you feel like cripple.
...experience working as a board, you know,
I always ask this question when things are not working well.
Even if I give you the artie p what are you going to do next.
Right are you...bunch of...burgers...got
...memory dumps and what's next...going to make sense out of it right so just giving already
p is not all visit enough and we thought we should try and do a
prototype of trying to build intelligence around this data-gathering and
the parse data based on the experience that we've
gained of supporting our customers for over multiple years and provides an prescriptive guidance
instead of just here's the article figure out yourself right and that's what this project basically started
with we started this project calling that as a...db project?
it is...preview the but we're trying to make an attempt to where we want to take
...next steps when and alert comes in what you do next
without just the restarting or engaging somebody or collins...
Okay, so, ...all tools available everybody knows what...should be logs.
Event...dot net dieter message...request tracing.
Application logs php logs management for app
inside could...how many of you are very...portal.
Call how many of used...or any of the other troubleshooting tools...backs.
I think there's quite a bit...
And, then we are partner solutions like neurologic...the z zero which we announced
...this week for profiling phd.
I'm not going to go through the most obvious ones today because it doesn't really help like in hb...for example,
...science not performing will getting exception it tells you here's the page five hundred this
...status code done what's next right I mean.
...trying to tell me right so...a good start is good started tells here's the pay that
...congo to...saying here's the
...five hundred is going to like what right so.
We're going to focus on this little part is what we call...aboard...
support site extension where we try to automate some part of it all right so.
This...start jumping to demos we'll spend the rest of assertion dune demos from
...okay so number eight area
okay this my management portal...this nice little site called
...buggy bakery which are nicely...application...to sell cakes
...like cakes...the if the resembles that the troubleshooting should be
...right and we'll try and find out how that works?
Okay, so, let's see what the...looks like a for those who are not the
are off every single website has a special endpoint.
Call...and that can be...by the
...name dot acm dot larger websites dot net.
When...teaches beautiful portal which is sort of your
...p into the machine right it gives you
...one available et cetera...when I go to the but consul when icc
and the or partial image you feel like home like now this is where I feel like I'm in a
server core windows I can do xyz?
You're still running in a sandbox but ...is...at least he gives you something to work with.
...you got a process explorer which is like
a task manager and you'll notice they're not too many processes appear right just wb and then there's another
...for the clue site which runs in a separate process that we...the one that
...your application...not many processes now because
the not many process running on the vm is because you're running inside a sandbox this
vm can be hosting hundreds of sites but each site cannot see any other
...of the only thing that you can see because you can to the could...of this bakery
...can only see what it owns in all the chide processes from that point on
...this is typically similar to task manager into a bunch of cool things look at the
modules look at the handles threads.
Environment even giving this is usually not enough and I can see cpu our memory going
...at what's next...
Is always...
Kill the process you can download the memory dump...locally, you know, what you need to do with it and,
then a bunch of...extensions...allows you to play with right so this is
clue in journal there is one...set
extension that I want to talk about so let's just as which...here?
And, switch to are...real demos from this point like, you know,
there's always a situation like, you know, your...going to a really big event...want to have...
insight into what is going on right a monitor...traffic that can be moved every few seconds
...first start...the any keeping an eye on your website
so for this the scenario let's go back ...see...built.
So, from...portal if you click on tools.
And, if you click on support it will do a re-direct.
With a single sign on for your site.
Little-bitty should come up to this aboard
...behalf variable list of all the sites that you have under the account
...logged in right all the subscription all the sites...and the first thing that you see right
of the backer is.
Observe.
What is...observe is basically
sulphur bigger solution that you guys build where v analyze your logs?
Every few seconds and then
...and categorize what success what is failure...coming
...some differences aggregate them together and start
displaying them life right and just to show you how that looks like I'm going to go and
...cancel out of from here in a start a low test.
On a site.
So, we just started...test I'm going to going switch to
that site from here and I think that site is in this subscription.
I'll switch to, yeah,
this is a specific...just basically switch the should switch the process to that guy
say...load the data and little-bitty we so the...load tessa...
...about ten seconds you will should start seeing the traffic that is coming to
...and...medium ride that rights within ten seconds whatever's happening
...aggregating what the...coming and you basically showing
...is getting three percent per second ramping up slowly andout of that were failing
...eighty-six twenty-five the...pbr office can monitoring the
libraries happening is a great start to start putting in something
bad wind right and then you can start using what you need to the beautiful
thing about this is like I said we do the aggregation across different gm's and all this stuff for you don't have
to do yourself you can switch.
By different host names so you see...is a different process
...that I've been sending to the clue site are...track here if I go to the actual site
...here if the site where to be a traffic...traffic manager I'll show you a little bit I have a
site where there's some load going on here these two site level to north and south.
Are behind the traffic manager I'll switch to that?
I...north and running a load test to a traffic manager
endpoints which is here already and you can see...it's everything seems to be go...
road is getting...forty-four requests per second now I can monitor the traffic
...the host names if my side
is multiple host names and I want to module for a given hosting
...the traffic coming from I can pick and choose if I choose this nothing's going to show up if I choose this
...and I...because no one's browsing with that the only thing that's been browsers this host name that's what my
...right and it's.
It's fantastic right...I go to level...right now been a assigned to this
...probably will be any...the point from their...so, yeah.
Like to...to the...can go through all...right so that's a good startso,
first the first step...observing we can do
as you can see there'sobvious transition from observe to analyze and to mitigate right so
to see what analyze can do let's move on...talk about a scenario.
Right.
...you basically now you...your website is all of a sudden performing slower...exceptions giving
error so what do I do next and how to...you will have available for that
...the specific thing?
I'm going to go back to my buggy big recite and let's change the
scope here again and to that guy.
You see and once you log in with
...all the subscription all the sites is one single place for you do start monitoring stuff from your
on here's the buggy...said I'm going to browse through it.
Looks fantastic and I'll try and order
...right...you see...spinning.
...to find out what's going on why this is spinning that's the next step to try and
...tools like frame how
...forever field request even tracing.
Okay, cool so I'll show you one little tricks it took fifteen
...up vogel my site through all settings.
Answer diagnostics the.
And, you'll see this little thing vehicle field request raising that have turned on the for
...one site turn that on I can actually go and set
up a good rules in other...I go to the clue endpoints by the way...you click on a...
where it's what more is running it location is and then go...from here on.
So, I'll go to my include endpoint
...command prompt sites ww.
And, I'll open of the web content file.
And, you'll see advert rules
that basically pace the to say in all trace everything in order one path.
Put all the providers trace all the providers and the
...definition status go-to hundred you can...a field a definition of a time taken you can say
...page takes more than twenty seconds then only traces
on tracing right now for every single requests in that and then there's another rule that basically...for five
...whatnot so since I had this...and...tracing the order one-page which
...to be this specific get order one
...cake I can go to my...a board site.
And, I see a fair blog here.
I will refresh and...a little bit to get the
logs back but he came up right away right here and when
...this guy you'll see the bunch of information your the tyne the try...
generated what was the url what was the work with the status quo and the time
...I can filter them...url time taken which...that alike if I look at this guy
...school down here...report that I got...here's the page that I was tracing?
For status...wondered that was a trigger status it was five...will give...five hundred...time thinking
...it says it took about fifteen seconds
to respond great if I go...you...will see the entire pipeline of dot
net what happened to that requests which all module tested what was the...body was
request headers right in things along those lines and I can start looking to
words spend most of the time from the time taken but I can do a little
trickier request detail and the different views...performance view and...
It took fifteen seconds inside the eight-minute pipeline leave right so it was
spending some time inside the...net biplanes processing if I click on view trace.
...me up I spend.
Time...lazy module right it's great it's a
...modular...but it's a good structured...like I said, you know,
you don't have to tell you the how to fix things...pointing to right direction and he and she will know what
he's changers...will know from the point I'm simply in this
...module under sleeping for fifteen seconds and
that's does that right it's a really simple situation here where on the order one-page
nicely just to prove points and now we purely any into one more layer
...see what's going wrong over here we can start
pone more layer and then there are other things and tricks situ and...when you want to trouble
...even more deeper and I'll get to that in a different scenarios one multi want to show you guys
is the event viewer how many of you didn't know that we have we had event your
roger but services there is event you're right it's just not visible in the portal
and is not there but I'll show you what it looks like and how to get there again support mortal aggravate
...here that's what I do here is basically grab the event
...that emitted from the application within this ambox across different
instances combine them together and present in one single you here you can
final filter I'm just like your windows the event your that you use to event
idea what not, you know, here's a another example?
Really early something the stupid that I'm doing with the...order that it feels.
Refresher and I should a little bit I should get the event here right this is the
event that happened...tells me and exception...dot and
because dot and logging is beautiful and it tells me here's where the game...misspelled
stack I call that stock which is fine but he I...on a...because I was doing...
devin wrong-way...gives you call...your typical dot net event that you want to goal
...so event yours present for every single side of all do the
aggregation from all the...
All right simple.
Stuff.
Let's move and see what's next
ok here's always million-dollar question I know why sites
being usually support for a huge click on one-page and...been spending spinning.
Some customer reports say hey I'm trying to
axes application of this part spinning you get on the machine you...and...the same
...you is already talking about right how do...solution that is always...always...unless,
you know, what exactly is happening inside that process that is serving this
...ad that given time...having that lightweight snapshot...
always helping can really...the...you can do a...debug none of that works
right the only thing...to get in the situation is probably some large cummings engaging there's a slow
...so page for x number of people and does that all right let's see we can do about that?
So, over here and I'm right now going to go and manually starreda
...some part of it but here's this is diagnostics...this is
the be for all the things that we've been talking about right now we're starting to get
Something more aggressiveon a diagnostic...diagnostics
...also recalled that as a...service where rightnow movie allow
you to do is configure what is important to you for that application
...locks memory dumps which is the
ww process that is hosting application http
log or php this might be phd application you don't care about the dot net in...can be
...for this was the absolute I go instead the configuration to memory dump.
This the...the service is nothing but
...little web job me call as a...runner is it is a little
warrior...this guy does that a knows based on a setting
...asking into collect.
...knows what to do with the
...just collected and build...report and try and make sense out of it right the reason I call him
a lawyer because this is feature that you use under really hostile situation
right when things are not working well in the vm is not something configuring this nice feature exit
...setting this guy in there when the memory spiking...abused biking the situation is really
bad entomol okay all right I'm going to go send you in there...the memory done
...this law...them over here...kill everything out there come back and tell me what
happened right fantastic most the time it works great.
But, there are situations where there's warrior will need help and if the if the wharf
...on is really, really bad you might not work, you know, eventually I do blind to make this guy
...democracy for a will get there but he's not there yet so.
This runner basically right now I'm coming in to go and collect the memory
...because that's what I care about...on a throughout this.
Infrastructure is completely extensible...I'll let me talk about
...after I show you what I mean so it makes more sense ok so let's see
...apps spinning slow I'm going to go back.
And, I'm going to reproduces situation I really hate chocolate cake right so that's why named...as
a deadlock cakes and I'm going to try and order the chocolate cake twice.
Here which...this once.
Now let me just try and get this guy here one more time.
Really quick before the situation here.
Ok, the seems to be spinning right.
And, now you...wiser spinning for whatever
reason if somebody else goes to different side the different...people working what
...do institute this situation you can come back here.
And, this site and this click on a single button that says something is
wrong diagnose now.
This is going out there and the submitted a session based on the settings that you provided
...static collecting the dumps right.
If you click on a diagnose number from this point on a basically going to go through all the
...that you have inside your sites if your
site scale to three or four or five is going to make a wrong number one number two number three
...before and just go get the data and try and make sense out of it
is eventually when it runs right so here you see...did finish generating the memory dumps and
...analyzing at this point if I were to go back to the diagnosis consul and the process
explorer I should be able to show you what I meant by extensibility you see
it's calling a dump analyzer javascript and this host
...has been running all of them is running...the chide with jobs right.
So, they should finish and a little bit while
...and it's done right so I can basically now expand this.
This is basically the whole memory number of the process and I can be built the
report based on.
What...found in that process that I'm going to go and click on that?
And, you'll see it found bunch of things and has a recommendations on top of...before I
started them why change the configuration on the...so I it knows that there was
the configured...that heck...the shutdown of the app domain which is fine
but here if I start reading into all the recommendations giving here and it tells,
you know, and, whatever possible gives you a link the
to an external location very talks about what happens one these sort
of situation occur and how you troubleshooting over here you can see is
...of the to...are basically waiting to enter a dot net
...has been held by thirty-four and a bunch of guys are trying to get into it into
...connections have been running for a long-time if I click on that will tell me which
connections yes I've been trying water?
The some
chocolate cake if I go back here again and click on the third thirty-four this holding the
lock it gives me a native call stack of what is happening on that...alongside with the
...right...tells me method be is holding some...channel enter
...and then other guys are basically.
Waiting on that.
Right and twenty-eight so if I go back into my code.
And, try and see where the lobbies...common here...method is basically rabin
...a...for an treasure...the b
...long the and...right...basically
...classing deadlock situation here but and even though it looks very
...the code perspective but e the tool has an ability to look at these
...read the call stacks and
identify the situations and start pointing you guys and what you need to do right if you were to show this
board to the developer wrote the code windows...you will exactly know what is wrong and how to fix
it right besides thosethe situations you so I showed you the
request is the work in-flight how long they've been running for the gc usage and all the other cool
...I'll go through the report one by one slowly here...the name of the...
what the architecture is what your top cpu threads are what...with through the
...cpu what you clr information is the how what threads in that situation
just a plot...what is to be context available
is pages been running on thread twenty-fourth is thirty-six if you click on...the cost act
...this is very...what has happened the situation is basically you just dumped...the
...given time and process was broken for that moment and as soon as the doubles
finish history...be executions from the client
perspective he or she just experienced of very slow delay and loading the page which
was not loading to begin with right so here, you know,
and, then it gives you all the dot net exceptions that are knob...garbage collector yet and,
things along those lines ucdavis connection strains?
...beautiful things...the at the height high-level it tries to tell you what
it following and what can be done to try and...specific issue from this point
on right and this all knowledge information is been build based on years and years
of troubleshooting with the actual customers when we understand and identify
...specific issue we try and automate the role into the engine and deploy inside this
a next time somebody else sees it he or she can basically try and figure out what
went wrong right so we this is a constant journey we keep updating...rules
...final patents keep on pushing them into...eventually...get...every
address ninety percent of the issues that are specific to app service but?
But,...a great start ok to this page finally field which is
timed afterwards so...scenario right if I go here and the...
...these are my sessions of this point great.
Let's see what's next we can do.
Right so this...great dougherty only works...with a dot length.
What if...phd
...can I use the same tool for phd?
So, let's try and see the what is the if I have I have a php
...to go...basically change the context.
...that specific guy.
it's a very simple wordpress like the flight's it right...browse...it's spinning,
spinning, spinning...wordpress...I can understand wide
...write-in amtrack I'll try and use the same technique that I
did in basically get the data for that too right so we'll just go
...the browse to a couple of times.
Okay, and, I come back...analyze...the settings I should have this page because I
...for this before yes it's just phd so you can see it setting is per
site is not tied to...said any of that again I can come here and
this click on diagnose...I can go to metrics...tab and I'll talk about...a little bit
...exactly is but I can see there's a specific instance only run
on a one instance right now so I'm...go and diagnose from here when I click submit
diagnosis from this point what I'm doing at this point is basically saying don't cry
...the session on all the instances that
I might have on the website just I just care about the specific guy because it doesn't look right
so I'm going to go initiate on that into taking the whole site downright I'll show you what looks like when we...too
often but they should have kicked off the session here for phd it's done and php
Fortunately is a very lightweight the process so for us in a debugging
is what we do not trying dump the phd process up because
we realize that on a given side they can be hundreds of phd running and dumping
...all-out is insane so we in-flight basically grab the
snapshot of the process and run the analyzer almost php and build
...right so let's see if this guy caught...
So, if I click on this...spicy...for
process running right already...were running the index esp page and
we can go to them one by one so I'll click on this guy...
Tells me again the environment variable with system up time
the process of time debug session it gives me a native call...the php with this trying
...do it seems like...trying to do some...file unlink
a operation trying to remove some file and delete a file.
Okay, that's interesting it tells me all modules unload inside the process right even this
...stop wordpress people usually have modules install.
...also tells me the handle information the cpu time here's the money part
...phd call...it tells me what happened to the page
...executed twice years line of code to action.
Capture hot there's a plugging...captures
...a clean-up right so that could be part of the reason why the
...slow so what I can do from this point on is just
go to this site the...could win point.
Ok,...sites...
Think...the wb content.
Uploads capture and just because I know
...plugging this is basically this guides highs to create...and take find everything that
was a comes in entice...and parceled on everything that was a...if I go into the
lead all these files because I don't needham delete star p and d.
...take a little because the tons and tons of...
But,...get...point I'm on a cohen refresh this and trying to leave that one more time off
And, once I deleted the performance of the page issued improve dramatically right
so let's try one more time because there's just way too many files in...the bp content.
Uploads capture.
All right let's to the leads...
The process running system might...use okay I'm going to go now and trying to control of five and see if
it performance improves a little bit.
And, it...was much better than previously I can go...the list that is that
...get the point right so it's usually helpful the not only...a dot net...of
spacey this it does a good...on troubleshooting phd as well.
...going to go enclose all the stuff out here before we move on to the next one
and also gives opc request information for that specific time the
...global variables if there was any lost error that was happening the permission...was trying to
...the processor itself was...permission...also...you guys give the...all right.
...want to show role quick.
...just the time...nondescript
...but I can show the there's a if your subscription or
...that you running has a my sequel database you can go to analyze seven we have a integration with
your db see if you click on is clearly b tab it tries
and calls the clearly be database and tells you what connections that are running I don't have a little...anything going
...you open connections if you've done any...nations...slow log entry size of a databases how much has been
...usually useful...well.
All right this one.
Ok, so, this is all great right now I can do bunch of things
when sites...or slow availability or exception.
But,...what if this things are happening in the middle-of-the-night what if it's happening to wanted-to
customers not everybody right when I come and get a...I try and see the sites up
...but some go customers complaining, you know, I don't want to do this I want you to automate this automatically
...some sort of customers who really don't care about
...find out what was going wrong as long as you can fix it right you just like just restarting
...restart just...to the automatically right.
And, that's where the mitigate the comes into picture
...is a feature called arguing.
And, I'm going to show you the ux the...for that recently.
This feature did not have a ux up until a few days ago.
It was only configured why ...file?
But, now...does which is good.
So, we just go back and...wife favorite...dn.
All right and the mitigate over here I can
set...rule-based on certain conditions right so now
I know that things when things are not working all I want to kick-off
of workflow instead of me come in and trying to get data automatically right so I'm
...to say...
And, when I do you'll see a bunch of situations like that I can capture I can see max...and
...for that and...number of requests
...taken action this is a vanilla scenario, you know,
you app after serving thousand requests is going to be crashing or doin'
memory legal whatever might as well just,
you know, if it serves thousand requests is in thirty seconds the setter rule antigen action?
So, let me just go back to this again slow
...a second one second scenario you can define number of
...classes in a given amount of timeframe in a given time in trouble
...if arm getting.
...the...is taken more than thirty seconds to serve in the last two minutes
there is definitely something raw help me out right so I can go and say like set of rules
in thirty-two courses take sixty seconds we serve last hundred-twenty
seconds.
Or something on the moment added...tells me coincide you action okay what all the actions we
support you can login event you can recycle or you can run a custom action.
The default custom action is you can run the...runner that we talked about that consul and...this guidance
is one of my favorite ones and we'll see the demo for...a little bit but what this guy this is,
you know, what when this condition is hit owned the vm
...the entire site right so you can have five workers running and one of them is
...acting bad and...worker is the one that's going to
...send a signal that I'm the one that's hitting this trigger you want tunica some actual
...consul with collect kill
and analyze right so let me just show you here what this guy does...I'm going to go
...data I'm going to kill the bad process and recover
...situation and then I'll analyze...this situation happened the middle-of-the-night
...you basically collect the data recovered yourself automatically and in the morning you read
you have the report...to help you understand what...wrong right so we'll see how this works...action real quick?
So, that's a slow requests going to
go on it and then status code again you can do number of requests is that give the hb
five hundred subset...status goes in this interval taken action which is
again very useful bunch of customer use...situation is well the majority of them really like
...request because it's a good way to understand or
to take the situation then there's one final one which is a my favorite one
...now I'm going to go and say that...memory of a products it right...bite so?
Most of time you end up getting customers right...you when you get a website in of the and the...to put as many
web says they can and there's always one bag I that takes of all the memory and a fix-all the other
guys right so it's hard to do basically go and ...come out but
you could basically use...tool to your advantage and the see if I can
reproduce issues I'm going to go and see if this guy five hundred
it goes about five hundred megabytes and once you take a custom action of
doing this right I'm going to go and the...just basically see update?
The rules been updated its and make sure it...anymore rules the only rule that I have is of
the process goes about five hundred megabytes take a custom action
...kill analyze.
All right so we go back to our famous back bakery application...this up.
And, I'll keep this keep this.
...doesn't hurt okay.
So, browser this application and I'm going to load test one specific page
...created...leak and all...what it looks like.
So, before we...we just go back here
in process explore try and show you what looks like.
This is our guide that within the bp right he's sitting
...megabytes forty-one thread count everything looks good go back here trying reproduce
setting about a thousand requests using tiny get to an order three-page and
...you should see a little bit if I go to analyze.
And, refresh.
Couple times probably bash in the load...already triggered the
...to find megabyte it started the collect workflow for me I don't have to do anything at this point
it's everything's working automatically...I go here
professes and I'll see this...probably gone bad really,
really bad...one-point-five gigabyte the
...consul kicked off in knowsley needs to do is going to go and collect the data
as soon...done collecting is going to call killed the process so the next
...experience from this will build a...and tell you exactly
what went wrong in the morning or whenever you...look at it and trying to fix it.
Okay,
so, it takes a little bit right because...what it's trying to dump one-point-one some gigabyte of data.
that's why I say it's a little...right does it does wonders even in the hostile situations but when things got really,
really bad is a to gigabyte right now it you might need some help
...and I'll show you how to help them out a little bit while that's
work in all show you the one that I had already created hopefully this is all now this is
...just now...this is it.
Let me see if this is it, yeah, had previously
ran this and while waiting for this to finish...go and show you what this looks like
...so here tells me thread twenty-nine skit of garbage collection fantastic, you know,
it's a tells...of us are looking to manage code source me on the context here right
as medien to a really, really bad point very has to kick-off garbage collection the cpu should be
eighty-one percent because uses kicked off here's a beautiful part again it tells you what you should be dawn how you
should halogen beautiful links wherever possible here I want to see what this consuming the most memory
at click on that until the system that web buddies to be context is taken that...thinking about
one-point-three gigabytes...six objects of those arrays here and it tells you again what
...finalizing q what is a large object
...those guys around a large job keep right so the only way...going to...on the
...to...and...to will only collect that guy
...not rooted right it doesn't seem like it has been collecting because it seems like it's been
...if I go back to my code and try and
...what exactly I'm trying to do here the...context.
We context let's go to the definition for this guy.
Yeah, I'm trying to add the context of every single-issue
request five hundred times into history object right.
Now...that's done I go to the definition for that here and see this
is static right is going to be routed it will never be collected right but people end up doing this
...mistakes right but...the point is if you show your
dev this specifics information is enough for them to...from that point on
right imagine trying to do all the stuff when the things...working well and production...debugged
...man it's usually not going to work and if it's if it's been you bring the devil and...what's happening is
...seattle right...our writing the...when you shown this, you know,
exactly what's going on but it gives you all the beautiful information possible those you should be storing of this thing
...not when trying to automate things as much as we can so we should go
back here to the process...here.
This bagged should've been gone by now yes it is I don't have the all...on turned on
so the new process hasn't kicked off and this should have finished it
has if I...click on this depending on wanted triggered
...I was lucky here to sign in third...the...a bunch of things and it's
highly because you've been...and the same exact same thing.
Right so it works every single time and I recommend you guys try this out the on
the different situations wherever possible lights and the water out into the vm...wonderland works
when it doesn't I'll show you how to recover from that situation as well because you probably
...hostile place to begin with
ok so let's go back here and let me show role quick how do you how you
...or get rid of that situation so you go back here and not to this guy.
...this close this close this.
This is a guy here.
...data folder.
And,...very logs reports and sessions are right I can go to...folder.
And, based on a date and time and I was executed I can download whatever I can go delete from your.
Yes, I have a feedback for myself as well I'm going to put the delete and right next to
...so you can get rid of it from that point on and yeah,
before now you can just basically delete these guys from here on and the moment
...a...session which...active complete and collect logs only collect
...one will all will be only activated when the das consul
...in active will have the sessions that are running right now completed the one that
...done you-can delete all the sections in one of the moment you do that
...not list into your the.
Session if you ever see that as a
...or the collection spinning,
spinning, spinning that never comes back because usually a very fascinating to watch that spinning because it's about tell
...something sometimes you might not because like I
...situation was back you can always go back in scale-up endow and the
...and will restart the thing and that's when you survived
or basically saved and from a bad situation ok
real quick and the matrix that I'll show you guys but I if I go back here to buggy bits
...basically say scale?
In...that's done I'm going to stop and start just
force tandy because the scaling takes a little bit yahoo this.
On down here.
Start.
...ok so that's coming up so now I should have for instances but if I get a metrics stabbing trying
...this guy.
A little bit I should be able to see
...for gm's that comes up this is different from the actual
...because now what you seen up here is that
site specific cpu memory on that instance what you see on the algebra
...is your combine cpu memory usage for that given
site over here you can come in and see what is specific to the given site
write the cpu memory every http statics again this will give you
...research will give you how many request has been served failed on the
ibm for that site instead of the entire aggregation is a great way to find out which
re m is busted which is taking how much traffic which is not doing develop and
...to invests most right it gives a network traffic and all the good seventy-four instances
there you...the short by one-hour twenty four hours.
Five minutes whatever tickles fancy over here and also we give you ability to reach
...wwe on that via right because when you go to the portal and try and start the
site is...take everything down and restart all the
...over here you can just say in what I want to restart just the bad guy on the end.
...that gives you five-second change...mind.
To wait and we'll call the wb and you'll start...great fantastic so that's how
we can do par vm you can diagnose per vm as well by looking at the memory cpu
...sets you get a good idea which is bad instead of doing a hammer of all the...take one out and,
...from that point on...so we how're running a little bit...a time I want
to touched...long-lasting we code that situation and the last thing is
this basically this...is what you do when all of this...we talk about we are top of
...and you tried all these things and you still is
...help we do in the situation right how many of you don't mind paying for the board
...support should be free...one...I denied this how do you think is ridiculous to
...reporting issue for live site or service issue the everyone pretty much,
yeah, we try to solve the...and we're working on the...eventually
yet that we try to solve the second part there's a live set issue and you really do want to
...don't have a simple contract you really want report something to somebody who's listening or
...compressible borrow click on need help right so like the subscription that has
issue like the side the seven issue.
What category...that your scene?
Will be more descriptive and help me
for us get an idea of any sense?
...sent an email alternative and we'll give you this little nine-one-one disclaimer of
...emergency please called the bohr I don't wait on us whatever right but,
at least when you do this there is and I'm going to show you got my inbox...just to prove that
...it works.
The...get sense out...my servicing team
...people who are actually monitoring the service whatnot in a little bit you'll see that here the
And, there are a bunch of people monitoring it...reply
are basically start working on the issue right away...available replies...five ten minutes
and to see if anybody wants to see and...so let me see go back here but, yeah,
that one way to report issue and, you know, we take that very seriously the services you will work on
it right away but if somebody asked me...I code this...and we're going to nicely tell you
...you work on that and part of to make the work.
So, I think, you know, I have covered the majority of the scenarios that I want to talk about there's more
...building but at this point in
...me just go back and make sure there's no more slight.
Yet there's an...brow than the we recommend...please give us feedback tell us what you like to see
will like to build that...whenever possible in a does that.
Yes.
I'll repeat the question.
Next question the question is sorry.
...excellent question the question was how does this diagnosis
servicecompare against things like app inside and things along those lines
...the app inside it basically something that you work into.
This basically on the other its...app insight right.
Not every customer will have app inside or any of that
the instrumentation running for the code from giggle even officially might not be completely
...truly optimized to basically capture all different situations...try to solve here is this
there's one very specific situation for everything's running...a production and you want to have
a very lightweight snapshot of what is exactly...without installing any tools without
...any the tracing anything...your the application just to
go at that specific time right so the app inside and everything works great
on the p the zen the profiling everything works create when you
tuna part request atroubleshooting and trying to find out what the...is
request and things along those lines the perfect question is how does work with multi the
...applications and we're trying to solve that one by one because what this does
...gives you snapshot of a web processes it ted culture to a point that if you're stuck on
top of database will say I'm making a...to database and I'm waiting to get
response back you will not tell you what exactly is wrong at this point on
...database on your query we try to solve that step by taking
a further collaboration with the clear...that you saw where they have
...diagnosis epa recall that does a connection test that does that tell you how many
connections open if anyone nation what not so the...information but we rely on
all the other environment to basically help us participate into this.
This project eventually have the full end-to-end the solutions like...optimal.
Now...at this is basically whatever's on the machine that you taken to take a
...if it happens I...the agent rights and the scripting on
a client-side browser and then get the data and then instrument from this on oct.
...and revolving.
That's correct...the all the other absolutes that are all then are basically using the same platform right so
they what like I said aboutbriefly touch to a point that this these framework
is extensible today if you have an application...application you...your own
locks and, you know, what exactly...to do with the law if some error happen in the log you can
want to tell your client do xyz you just write the collector you...the parser you
uploaded...I don't have a us to show how...can be file and you are part of the system now right so now
...basically participating in this framework in the all you have to decide the collector,
you know, where you log one, you know, what the engine log means write the collector write the partial
...report and you can pretty much plug-and-play in this?
...every mobile app or anybody else, you know,...able eventually they want to the can
part participate into it right a node collector node parser there's nothing stopping you from doing that.
And, then you can take advantage of this auto healing triggers that we talked about and
then trigger your analyzers and collector instead of the one that I in the box.
Hra questions thanks.
All right thanks lawson moi.
So, it's a good question the question was the...holding rule that I was setting up do they go instead of a
...the answer
is no actually previously when we didn't have the ux via large you to put those rules
...other convict when you do this from the ux it goes inside the application
...can pick file so if you...said the role using the ux and also set one with the
...the one in the web configures going-to-take the president's right so this actually large
...flexibility of running multiple
custom actions today with arguing if you were just in a web
...app is you can only on one custom action for multiple triggers but now you can
...few triggers and...matching apples and the one that's important you
can have...web convicts and algal monitor both of them and you get a flexibility of doing more advanced
...if you need to moi.
...the question...do does clue work with the are back the answer to is today
...you need to be aside administrator to log on to the
...the to perform xyz but like I said this feature that we building
...to called the...a prototype is an preview but
...eventually move this into portal and when we do that the
our backs scenario will command and where you allow people to do this for the...
Sorry can you please repeat the question.
Excellent question so yes there are there are api...available and I'll show you the
command-line available for certain scenarios especially for the as one of
the diagnostics ones so if I go to see.
The mitigate in the...
Will...my blog...the talks about the command-line...that is available right now I include
...for bunch of api things that you can do restarting the process and calling things
along those lines but here there's a canal...that you can do use and, you know,
and, that's what I've been using for custom action in custom actually would choose to run...only
...if you lighted...something that we prebuilt...
All right cool thanks thank you.